<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>English on OKF</title>
    <link>https://beta.okfn.de/tags/english/</link>
    <description>Recent content in English on OKF</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-DE</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://beta.okfn.de/tags/english/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OffeneGesetze: Opening Germany&#39;s Law Gazette (Update)</title>
      <link>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/2018/12/offenegesetze-opening-germanys-law-gazette-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/2018/12/offenegesetze-opening-germanys-law-gazette-update/</guid>
      <description>Update, 12/24/2018: In response to OffeneGesetze, the German Ministry of Justice has announced that it will create a digital legislative process in the coming years. The ministry is creating a platform on which federal law gazettes &amp;ldquo;can also be freely printed, searched and re-used&amp;rdquo;. There should be unrestricted access, the Justice Minister Katarina Barley said.
The Federal Law Gazettes are the central documents of German democracy. To pass a law, it has to be published in the Law Gazette.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening the Democratic Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/2018/12/strengthening-the-democratic-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/2018/12/strengthening-the-democratic-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>2018 proved, again, why we need to strengthen the infrastructure for democracy. This year, our freedom of information project FragDenStaat has revealed how the Ministry of Family Affairs cooperates with the Domestic Intelligence Service, we have published the Ministry of the Interior&#39;s Master Plan on Migration and documents on “concentration camp-like prisons”&amp;nbsp;in Libya.
Democracy is not only under fire in the USA or Brazil, but also in Germany. And yet there is too little controversy about how we can expand democratic structures in this country.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Publication to Award - The story of the missing information in the tender cycle</title>
      <link>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/2016/07/from-publication-to-award-the-story-of-the-missing-information-in-the-tender-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/2016/07/from-publication-to-award-the-story-of-the-missing-information-in-the-tender-cycle/</guid>
      <description>Billions of euros are spent on procuring for public goods. Our research shows that some of the procurement could be done more efficient and hence cheaper. Here, having information on the whole public procurement cycle is essential to evaluate the process and monitor it properly. Without information on contract implementation such as the final price paid and completion date, any assessment is incomplete hence can be misleading.
When most of the people think about public procurement they either think of the result (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who has won the contract? - Identifying the bidders of public procurement processes</title>
      <link>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/2016/06/who-has-won-the-contract-identifying-the-bidders-of-public-procurement-processes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/2016/06/who-has-won-the-contract-identifying-the-bidders-of-public-procurement-processes/</guid>
      <description>In the last couple of years there has been a strong push by political leaders and civil society towards making beneficial ownership more transparent. There are various very good reasons for this, varying from making it more difficult to disguising the beneficiary of transactions, or using shell companies for illicit purposes such as money laundering and hiding stolen assets. In the arena of public procurement there is the suggestion to start by publishing beneficial ownership for bidders for public tenders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OKF at the OGP Summit - Have your say and vote for the sessions you want to see happening at the summit</title>
      <link>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/1/01/okf-at-the-ogp-summit-have-your-say-and-vote-for-the-sessions-you-want-to-see-happening-at-the-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://beta.okfn.de/blog/1/01/okf-at-the-ogp-summit-have-your-say-and-vote-for-the-sessions-you-want-to-see-happening-at-the-summit/</guid>
      <description>How can we make governments more transparent and accountable? What are tried and true strategies for opening up government data? The annual OGP summit is an opportunity for the open government community to address its current issues and challenges, and discuss the way ahead. This year, the summit will be held in December in Paris, and you can have your say in shaping the agenda. Together with our friends and partners like g0v.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>