<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Projects on OKF DE</title>
  <link rel="self" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/"/>
  <updated>1970-01-01T00:33:34+0000</updated>
  <author>
    <name>YOUR NAME HERE</name>
    <email>YOUR EMAIL ADDRESS</email>
    <uri>DEFINITIVE URI OF YOUR WEB SITE</uri>
  </author>
  <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/</id>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Open Gov Netzwerk</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/ogp/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/ogp/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>As part of the Open Government Network, we support Germany&amp;rsquo;s active participation in the Open Government Partnership (OGP) and the interests of German civil society in this process and coordinate the civil society network.
The network is an association of civil society organisations and individuals that has been working since 2011 to promote open government and administrative action as a holistic approach to strengthening democracy. In particular, the focus is on the exchange with the Federal Government and the development of national action plans.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Code for Germany</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/codeforde/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/codeforde/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Code For Germany is a network of groups of volunteer volunteers (Labs) who use their skills to positively shape their cities and social life. They advocate more transparency, open data and participation in their cities. In particular, they mediate between civil society, administration and politics and use their skills to improve communication between them and to provide the necessary impetus so that as many people as possible can benefit from the possibilities of open and free digitisation.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>FragDenStaat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/fragdenstaat/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/fragdenstaat/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>In a democracy, it is necessary for citizens to be able to inform themselves freely about government actions. With the Freedom of Information Act, every person, regardless of age or origin, has the right to request documents from the authorities. With the FragDenStaat online platform, we support citizens in exercising their right to access information from German authorities. Citizens no longer have to work their way through the legal jungle of the federal states and the federal government to make a request.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Prototype Fund</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefund/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/prototypefund/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>With the Prototype Fund we support socially relevant software projects and increase their sustainable impact through open source as a matter of principle. In short: We support Public Interest Tech. We make digital-social innovation possible; with developer groups that bring a wide range of skills to bear in technology design and pass on their good ideas. With up to 47,500 euros per project and team, the funding fund supports software developers, hackers and creative people in implementing sketches for tools and applications in the areas of Civic Tech, data literacy, IT security and software infrastructure.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Demokratielabore</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/demokratielabore/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/demokratielabore/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>The &amp;ldquo;Demokratielabore&amp;rdquo; or Democracy Labs is a pilot project for adolescents between the age of 12 and 21. We aim to foster self-efficacy and empower young people by using technology for democracy. We strive to let children and young adults experience their own digital skills as a powerful tool to get involed in a democratic society as active and self-determined members. To reach that goal we organize workshops, establish working groups and run an online tv channel.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Jugend hackt</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/jugendhackt/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/jugendhackt/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Jugend hackt is a program designed to support young coders.
While such competitions as ‘Jugend musiziert’ (Music) and ‘Jugend forscht’ (Science) have been established in Germany for decades, there are few intiatives directed towards young talent in the field of software development. To fill this gap, Open Knowledge Foundation Deutschland e.V., together with the media education agency, Mediale Pfade, organized the first Jugend hackt event in 2013. Since then, it has become a successful and well-established hackathon for young coders from all over Germany.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Zugang gestalten</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/zuganggestalten/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/zuganggestalten/</id>
    <published>1970-01-01T00:33:34+0000</published>
    <updated>1970-01-01T00:33:34+0000</updated>
    <summary>Museums, archives, libraries and momuments are operated and maintained with public funds. The international conference &amp;lsquo;Zugang gestalten&amp;rsquo; asks the question whether this is adequately reflected in the level of access to the cultural treasures that these institutions possess and maintain. The conference invites key figures in culture, science, civic society and politics to publicly explore different ways of accessing digital cultural heritage in Germany.
&amp;lsquo;Zugang gestalten&amp;rsquo; stands under the auspices of the German UNESCO commission and is a collaboartive project of the Open Knowledge Foundation Deutschland, Stiftung Historische Museen Hamburg, Servicestelle Digitalisierung Berlin, Deutschen Digitalen Bibliothek, Internet &amp;amp; Gesellschaft Collaboratory e.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>2030watch</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/2030-watch/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/2030-watch/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>2030Watch monitors the implementation of the Sustainable Development Goals (SDGs) in Germany. The SDGs were set by the United Nations in September 2015 to be implemented by 2030. All members of the United Nations have committed to realizing these 17 goals and 169 targets. The goals include the eradication of poverty and inequality between and within countries as well as action against climate change. 2030Watch primarily uses data from the OECD, the World Bank and other international organizations.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Apps and the city</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/appsandthecity/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/appsandthecity/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>&amp;lsquo;Apps and the City&amp;rsquo; was a hackday on local traffic organized by OKF DE together with the local transport provider VBB, the Berlin government and the FH Potsdam. The VBB released GTFS data, opened up their API and provided some geo datasets about entrances to stations. During the event, coders, software experts, and designers used open transport data to create applications intended to non-commercially improve public transport.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Apps for Europe</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/appsforeurope/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/appsforeurope/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Apps for Europe was a program intended to showcase the impact of open data in terms of its economic potential. Neelie Kroes, former Vice President of the European Commission and a strong supporter of Apps for Europe, quantifies the value of open data several billion Euros. The Consortium behind Apps for Europe wants to facilitate the exploration of the value of open data by helping entrepreneurs to transform their ideas into successful businesses, that can gain foothold all over Europe.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>BIG</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/big/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/big/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Big Data Public Private Forum (BIG) is working towards the definition and implementation of a clear strategy that tackles the necessary efforts in terms of research and innovation, while also it provides a major boost for technology adoption and supporting actions for the successful implementation of the Big Data economy.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Bundesgit</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/bundesgit/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/bundesgit/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>This git repository contains all German federal laws and regulations in markdown format. The XML version of these laws available on gesetze-im-internet.de serves as the source. With BundesGit the most current version of the laws is saved. Hereby, their historic development and adaptation is transparent and easily comprehensible.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Coding da Vinci</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/codingdavinci/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/codingdavinci/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Coding da Vinci is the first cultural data hackathon in Germany bringing together cultural heritage institutions and the hacker/designer community to develop ideas and prototypes for the cultural sector and the public. More and more galleries, libraries, archives and museums (GLAMs) are digitalizing their collections to make them accessible online and to preserve our heritage for future generations. Only when cultural data is made openly available (according to the Open Definition) can it serve as the creative basis for innovative new applications and projects.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>D-EITI</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/eiti/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/eiti/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>The global Extractive Industries Transparency Initiative (EITI) advocates greater financial transparency and accountability in the extractive sector.
The initiative, which was founded in 2003 as part of the 2002 Sustainability Summit in Johannesburg, South Africa, is based on close cooperation between governments, companies and civil society in over 50 countries. They disclose information on tax payments, licenses, production volumes and other important data relating to the extraction of oil, gas and mineral resources.</summary>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>DARIAH-DE</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/dariah/"/>
    <id>https://beta.okfn.de/en/projekte/dariah/</id>
    <published>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</published>
    <updated>0001-01-01T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>DARIAH-DE supports digitally-enabled research and teaching in the arts and humanities. For this purpose, the project is developing a research infrastructure in support of service and research data as well as materials for research and teaching in the Digital Humanities. DARIAH-DE is the german national contribution to the European research infrastructure &amp;ldquo;DARIAH-EU - Digital Research Infrastructure for the Arts and Humanities&amp;rdquo; within the framework of ESFRI.
As a project partner, we support DARIAH-DE with the communication and dissemination of the allignment, content, and results of the digital humanities.</summary>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
